<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2026 Treesys -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.treesys.arborito</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-only</project_license>
  <name>Arborito</name>
  <summary>Learn anything as an interactive tree of lessons</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Aprende cualquier tema como un árbol interactivo de lecciones</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Arborito turns any subject into a visual map of lessons you explore at your own pace.
      Study from community trees, plant your own, translate lessons, or remix what others published.
    </p>
    <p>
      Free and open source under GPL v3. Local-first by default: your progress stays on your device.
      No subscription, no mandatory account, no ads.
    </p>
    <p>
      The desktop build adds optional local Sage AI tutoring and high-quality voice on capable hardware.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="es">
      Arborito convierte cualquier tema en un mapa visual de lecciones que exploras a tu ritmo.
      Estudia árboles de la comunidad, planta el tuyo, traduce lecciones o remezcla lo que otros publicaron.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="es">
      Gratis y de código abierto bajo GPL v3. Local-first por defecto: tu progreso permanece en tu dispositivo.
      Sin suscripción, sin cuenta obligatoria, sin anuncios.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="es">
      La app de escritorio añade tutoría opcional con Sage IA local y voz de alta calidad en equipos capaces.
    </p>
  </description>
  <developer id="org.treesys">
    <name>Treesys</name>
  </developer>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.treesys.arborito.desktop</launchable>
  <url type="homepage">https://arborito.org</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/treesys-org/arborito/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/treesys-org/arborito</url>
  <url type="help">https://github.com/treesys-org/arborito/blob/master/README.md</url>
  <update_contact>support@treesys.org</update_contact>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="social-chat">moderate</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
  <categories>
    <category>Education</category>
  </categories>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>education</keyword>
    <keyword>learning</keyword>
    <keyword>lessons</keyword>
    <keyword>curriculum</keyword>
    <keyword>open source</keyword>
    <keyword>local-first</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.1.0-alpha" date="2026-07-08">
      <description>
        <p>Initial public alpha: interactive lesson maps, local-first progress, optional Sage AI on desktop.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
